(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
重大発表 3DLIVE
Major Announcement 3DLIVE
やんない、じゃない、できないんだ。どや！
It's not that I won't, it's that I can't. So there!
ダダダダ天使
作詞・作曲：ナユタン星人
Dada Dada Tenshi
Lyrics & Composition: Nayutalien
バカばっかり！地元でうわさのダメ天使
Just idiots! The no-good angel famous in the neighborhood
ダメの子守唄　シノバパワーで補ってく
Lullaby for a no-good kid, making up for it with Shinova power
のよ。天使さ！
That's me. An angel!
できないの　もっともっとあなたに気に入ってほしい
I can't do it, I want you to like me more and more
退屈で　腐りすぎたら　ビビる　コミュニケーション
If I get too bored and rotten, I get scared of communication
天使のリングの停電は　切れかけてるけど
The power outage of my angel ring is about to go out
見方を変えれば　これもう愛、愛、愛、愛さ！
If you change your perspective, it's already love, love, love, love!
なんて強がった　本当は曖昧な愛の感情も
Acting tough like that, even my truly ambiguous feelings of love
あなたと探したいの
I want to search for them with you
ねえ　ダメダメダメダメな私を　愛してね
Hey, please love me, the no-good, no-good, no-good me
大概の賞賛は　右から左へ受け流してさ！
Just let most of the praise pass from right to left!
ドキドキドキドキをあげるよ　あなたには
I'll give you heart-pounding, heart-pounding excitement
ちゃんと見ててくれるなら　だむ、だむ、だむ
If you're watching me properly, damu, damu, damu
ダダダダダメ天使！　ダダダダダメですか？
Dada Dada no-good angel! Dada Dada, is it no good?
だけど、もう私はいいか！　やんない、じゃない、できないんだ。どや！
But well, I'm fine already! It's not that I won't, it's that I can't. So there!
テストでいい点とりたい！　でも頭がちっとも追いつかない
I want to get a good score on the test! But my brain doesn't keep up at all
日曜日だって早起きしたい！　深夜のネトゲがやめられない
I want to wake up early even on Sundays! I can't stop playing online games late at night
やる気がないとかそんなんじゃなくて　やる気があってもできない性
It's not that I don't have motivation, it's that even if I do, I'm the type who can't do it
しょうがないな、って許してよ　エンジェルリング　放り投げて
Forgive me, saying 'it can't be helped'. Throwing away my angel ring
天使の翼は使ってない　飛ぶの怖いから
I don't use my angel wings because I'm afraid of flying
本気も出したら飛べますが？　みたいな顔しているんだ
I'm making a face that says, 'I could fly if I really tried, you know?'
表と裏の裏側で隠した
Hidden behind the front and back...
愛の感情があなたに笑ってほしいの
...is a feeling of love that wants you to smile.
ねぇ ダメダメダメダメな私をいいですか？
Hey, is it okay if I'm a good-for-nothing?
一切合切の自信もないような天使ですが
I'm an angel with absolutely no confidence,
ゴロゴロゴロゴロと回る頭の中では
But inside my head, spinning round and round...
あなたのことばかり考えてるんだ
...I'm thinking only about you.
ダメダメダメダメな私を愛してよ
Please love me, a good-for-nothing me.
貰った愛でもっともっと冬を天使だから
Because I'm an angel who'll make winter warmer with the love I receive.
ドキドキドキドキをあげるよ あなたには
I'll give you a heart-pounding sensation.
もっと気になってくれるのなら どこまでも飛ぶ
If you care more about me, I'll fly anywhere.
ダダダダダメ天使 ダダダダダメ天使
Da-da-da-da-damned angel! Da-da-da-da-damned angel!
だけど そんな私でもいいかな？
But is it okay if I'm like this?
なーんちゃってじゃない できないんだとや
Just kidding! I'm not useless! ...Actually, I am.
や、でも努力はしますとや
Well, but I'll do my best!
みなさんどうも！こんあくあー！
Hello everyone! Kon-aqua!
見えてますかー？こんばんはー！
Can you see me? Good evening!
みんなということで今日は来てくれてありがとう 湊あくあです！
Everyone, thank you for coming today. I'm Minato Aqua!
わぁー！すごいコメントが。はい！
Wow! So many comments. Okay!
ということで1曲目ね もうね あの序盤から「ダダダダ天使」歌わせていただいたんですけども
So for the first song, right from the start, I sang "Dadadada Tenshi".
ちょっとね まだまだね 今日は歌っていくので みんな楽しんでってもらえると嬉しいです！
I'll be singing more today, so I hope you all enjoy it!
そして最後ね こちらね 湊あくあ重大発表とあるように 最後に重大な発表もございますので お楽しみに！
And at the end, as the title "Minato Aqua Major Announcement" says, I have a big announcement, so look forward to it!
おっ、おっ、おおっ、およよよよ、およよ、おっ、あれ！？
Oh? Oh? Ohhh? O-yo-yo-yo-yo... Huh!?
なんか浮いてる。あれ！？なんなんだこいつは。あれ？
Something's floating. Huh!? What is this thing? Huh?
なんか最近いつも3Dの時は常連になっている気がする 猫！猫がいる！
I feel like it's always a regular during my 3D streams lately. A cat! There's a cat!
あれ？猫も私のライブ応援しに来てくれたの？
Oh? Did the cat come to support my live concert too?
猫だー！あ、すごいすご飛躍跳ねてる。あら、猫。
It's a cat! Oh, it's jumping around like crazy. Well, hello cat.
あと、なんかもうさ レギュラー入りしてんじゃん どういうこと？
Besides, you're like a regular member now. What's going on?
どうしちゃったんだよ、えー！？ちょっとどこ行くの？
What's wrong? Eh!? Hey, where are you going?
ちょちょちょちょ...なになに？そんな動き回って何よ 猫！ちょっと あ、どこ行ったんだけど！
Whoa whoa whoa... what? Why are you moving around so much, Cat! Hey, where did it go!
猫ー！ちょっとー！
Cat! Hey!
ちょっと！猫！猫！はぁ...はぁ...ちょっと あれ？ここがどこ？
Wait! Cat! Cat! *pant* *pant* Wait... huh? Where am I?
なんかいつの間にか知らないところに来ている 知らない天井がある
Before I knew it, I ended up somewhere I don't know. There's an unfamiliar ceiling.
あれ ちょっと待って 猫を追いかけてたらなんか...どこ ここ？わかんない 私は誰？ここは何処？あれ？
Wait a minute... I was chasing the cat and then... where is this? I don't know. Who am I? Where is here? Huh?
ちょっと みんなのいるステージに早く戻らないと
I need to get back to the stage where everyone is, and fast!
うっ...頭が...なのに帰り道が思い出せない
Ugh... my head... but I can't remember the way back.
私 どうしたらいいのー！？
What should I do!?
どうしたらいいの なに？ちょっと 何？お芝居じゃないから全然
What should I do? What? Hey, what? This isn't an act at all!
あれ？はっ！わぁー！こんなところに なんか怪しげな いかにも怪しげな小瓶がある
Huh? Oh! Wow! In a place like this, there's a suspicious, very suspicious-looking bottle.
えー なんだこれ よっこいしょ うわぁ いかにも怪しげな すごくペラペラに見えなくもない 小瓶
Ehh, what's this? *heave-ho* Whoa, it looks really suspicious, almost like it's made of paper, this bottle.
ある。
There is one.
なんだろう、これ。
I wonder what this is.
瓶の中身を飲めば、
If you drink the contents of the bottle,
帰り道がわかるはず。
you should be able to find your way home.
え？
Eh?
なんだこれ、脱出ゲーム始まった、もしかして。
What's this? Did an escape game start?
やばい、どうしよう、みんな。
Oh no, what should I do, everyone?
デスゲームが始まる！まずい！
A death game is starting! This is bad!
ほう、ほう、ほう、ほう。
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
全部で3つの謎解きに挑戦しますと。ほう、なるほど。
I'll be challenged with three riddles. I see.
そして3つ目の謎を解くことで、
And by solving the third riddle,
箱を開けて、瓶の中身を飲める。
I can open the box and drink the bottle's contents.
そして、なんと途中でゲストから、
And unexpectedly, in the middle, from a guest...
ヒントがもらえる。
I can get a hint.
は？
Huh?
すごい、なんか脱出ゲーム始まっちゃったんだけど。
Wow, an escape game has started.
えー、マジか。マジか。
Eh, seriously? Seriously.
どんな問題が出るんだ。一旦ちょっと置いといて。
I wonder what questions... for now, I'll put this down.
これ、まだ使えないみたいだ、これ。
It seems I can't use this yet.
何の問題が出るんだろう。
I wonder what kind of problem it will be.
ふしぎの国からの脱出
Escape from Wonderland
何でもかかってこいよ。謎解きでしょ？
Bring it on! It's a riddle, right?
IQ 5000の私に任せたら楽勝よ。
If you leave it to me with an IQ of 5000, it's a breeze.
あ、何、何、何？
Ah, what, what, what?
お、これか？謎が。
Oh, is it this? The riddle...
お、来た！
Oh, it's here!
急に来るな、はい。
Don't come so suddenly. Okay.
この人物に次の謎を伝えておく。
Convey the next riddle to this person.
3 < 4 < 5 < 6 < 7 < 8 < 9 < 10
< 11 < 12 < 13 < 1 < 2
誰に声をかける？
Who do I talk to?
声をかけられるのは1人だけ。
You can only talk to one person.
え？どういうこと？
Eh? What does that mean?
おじいちゃんと...
An old man and...
なんだこれ、お金持ち、お金持ち。
What's this? A rich man, a rich man.
マッチョ。
Macho.
メガネの人。
Glasses person.
え、どういうこと？やばい、どういうこと？
Eh, what does it mean? What does it mean?
3からの4、からの5、からの6...
From 3 to 4, to 5, to 6...
なんかさ、これさ、3がさ、
It kind of looks like 3 is...
4ってしゃべってるみたいだね。違うか。
saying "4", doesn't it? Or not.
言ってる意味わかんない人のほうがほとんどだよね。
Most people probably don't know what I'm saying.
え、どういうことだ？
Eh, what does it mean?
3からの4、からの...
From 3 to 4, from...
え？
Eh?
なんだろう、なんで1じゃないんだろう。
I wonder... why isn't it 1?
なんで13のあとがこれ1なの？
Why is it 1 after 13?
え、どういうことだ？13のあとが1で、2で...
Eh, what does it mean? After 13 is 1, then 2...
だから3が一番小っちゃいってことだよね、これ。3が一番小っちゃくて、
So it means 3 is the smallest, right? 3 is the smallest,
で2が一番大きい。
and 2 is the largest.
え？
Eh?
なんだ？
What?
おじいちゃん、声をかけれる。おじいちゃん？
Old man, I can talk to him. Old man?
もしもし、おじいちゃん？
Hello, old man?
お金持ちの人？
The rich person?
もしもし？
Hello?
マッチョ？もしもし？
Macho? Hello?
え、どういうことだ？
Eh, what does it mean?
3が小さい、4...
3 is small, 4...
2が...
2 is...
あ、間違えて、間違えて、間違えて。
Ah, my mistake, my mistake, my mistake.
3が小さくて、2が大きいんでしょ？
3 is small and 2 is large, right?
で、この4人の中...
And among these four people...
答えは！
The answer is!
2個目の、お金持ち。つまりこれ、大富豪でしょ？
The second one, the rich man. In other words, "Daifugo"?
トランプだ、これ。
It's a card game.
正解？
Correct?
やった！
Yes!
あれ、楽勝か、マジで。え？
Wow, was that a breeze? Seriously. Eh?
私、賢い。IQ 5000！
I'm smart. IQ 5000!
ほら、私、賢いかも、もしかして。
Look, maybe I am smart after all.
あら、これ、簡単ならすぐ脱出しちゃうぞ、これ。
My, if it's this easy, I'll escape in no time.
開始10分で脱出しちゃうべ、これ。えー。
I'll probably escape within 10 minutes. Eh.
ちょっと次行くか、ちょっと。早く帰りたいよ、私。
Let's go to the next one. I want to go home.
ライブしなきゃいけないんだよ、私。
I have to do a live stream!
あ、そういうこと？
Ah, is that it?
早く、早く、帰して、ここから脱出！
Hurry, hurry, let me go home! Escape from here!
うわ、毒キノコ出てきた。
Whoa, poisonous mushrooms appeared.
このキノコを食べれば、次の謎が現れる。
If you eat this mushroom, the next riddle will appear.
ただし、食べられるのは一つだけ。
However, you can only eat one.
ほかは毒がある。
The others are poisonous.
いかにも全部毒がありそうな色してる。
They all look like they'd be poisonous.
茶色しか、なんか食べられそうな色なくない？
Doesn't only the brown one look edible?
紫とか、絶対やばいでしょ。え、どういうこと？
Purple is definitely dangerous. Eh, what?
茶色、紫、オレンジ、緑...
Brown, purple, orange, green...
青足す黄は、バツ。
Blue plus yellow is X.
青足す赤は、バツ。
Blue plus red is X.
赤足す黒は、バツ。
Red plus black is X.
黄足す赤は、マル。
Yellow plus red is O.
え、どういうことだ？
Eh, what does it mean?
なんだこれ。
What is this?
バツ、バツ、マル、バツ。色...
X, X, O, X. Color...
ちょっとゲスト呼んでみる。
I'll try calling the guest.
ゲスト呼んでみる。
ここでさ、1発目、1個目の問題さ、簡単にクリアしちゃったらさ、
If I clear the first problem too easily right here,
ちょっとさ、ゲストの出番なくなっちゃうかもしれないから、ちょっとゲスト呼んでみる？
the guest might not have anything to do, so should I call them now?
ちょっと、じゃあ...
Wait, well then...
ゲストの、ちょっとライフライン！プリーズ！
Guest, help! Lifeline, please!
プリーズ、ゲストの人！
Please, guest!
ゲストの方、スタッフ...スタッ、スタッフ...？
Guest person, staff... sta... staff...?
アンデデ～、あくあ様。
Andede~, Aqua-sama.
「あたし賢いIQ 5000」とか言ってませんでしたっけ？
Didn't you say, "I'm smart, I have 5000 IQ"?
アンデデ～。
Andede~.
その声は、その声は...
That voice, that voice...
チョコちゃん！？
Choco-chan!?
はーい。ホロライブ2期生、悪魔の保健医、癒月ちょこです！ということでね。
Hi. I'm Hololive's 2nd generation, the demon nurse, Yuzuki Choco! So...
待って、待ってよ。
Wait, wait a minute.
お、ライフライン、ヘルプって言われて呼ばれてきたんですけど、あれ？
I was called here as a lifeline, but oh?
天才のあくあ様に、これ、ヒントいります？
Does the genius Aqua-sama really need a hint for this?
何？
What?
いる、ね？
I do, okay?
一応言っといてよ。あたし分かんないの。
Just say it. I don't get it.
あくあ様、あたし、分かる、もうちょっと考えれば分かるけど、
Aqua-sama, I... I'd know if I thought about it a bit more, but...
でもだってさ、もし出番なくなっちゃうかもしれないから、呼んであげたんだよ。
But you see, I called you because you might not have had a turn otherwise.
あ、本当に？優しいあくあ様。
Oh, really? Kind Aqua-sama.
やばい、完全にバカにされてる。チョコちゃん、これ分かんの？
Geez, she's totally making fun of me. Choco-chan, do you know this?
いやもう、チョコは余裕ですよ、こういうのは。任せてほしい。
No, Choco can handle this easily. Just leave it to me.
ヒントは？ヒント、1個だけ、1個、1個ヒント、1個1個...
What about a hint? One hint, just one, one hint...
あ、あくあ様。よく見てみて。
Ah, Aqua-sama. Look closely.
はい、よく見た。
Yes, I'm looking.
よく見たら、なんか、丸に色が付いてませんか？
If you look closely, aren't those circles colored?
はい、色付いてます。青とか赤とか付いてます。レッド、ブルー、イエロー、
Yes, they are. There's blue and red. Red, blue, yellow,
ブルー、イエロー、イエロー、ブルー、
blue, yellow, yellow, blue...
なんか、その色の真ん中に「＋」って付いてるから、
Since there's a "+" in the middle of those colors,
それ混ぜたら、何色になるんでしょうね？
what color would it be if you mixed them?
うーん。
Hmm.
え、じゃあ...
Eh, well then...
え、じゃあさ、最初の青色と黄色を混ぜると何色ですか？
Well, what color do you get if you mix blue and yellow?
青と黄色は...分かんない。
Blue and yellow... I don't know.
緑！緑！緑！緑！
Green! Green! Green! Green!
あぁ、よかった。緑色ね。うんうん。
Ah, good. Green, right. Uh-huh.
そういうことか！あ、そういうことか！
So that's it! Oh, I see!
じゃあ赤と黒は？
Then what about red and black?
赤と黒は...黒。
Red and black is... black.
お、OK、OK。
Oh, OK, OK.
じゃあ青たす赤は？
Then blue plus red?
紫！
Purple!
紫。ちなみに、あの赤たす黒、あれ、今「黒」って言った、もしかして？あれ？
Purple. By the way, about red plus black... did you just say "black"? Wait.
茶色、茶色、茶色、茶色、茶色！
Brown, brown, brown, brown, brown!
あ、茶色。OK OK。なるほど！あ、そういうことか！
Oh, brown. OK, OK. I see! Ah, that's it!
はいはいはいはいはい！じゃあ最後の黄色たす赤は？
Yes, yes, yes! Then the last one, yellow plus red?
オレンジ！
Orange!
正解でーす！
That's correct!
やったー！あ、オレンジか！はーい！
Yay! Oh, it's orange! Okay!
いやもう、流石IQ 5000。分かってたんだね。
As expected of 5000 IQ. You knew it, didn't you?
分かってたんだけどね。みんなにもね、やっぱね、あの...
I knew it all along. I just wanted to show everyone...
ちゃんとね、そう、番組のことを考えてね、ちゃんとクリアしてあげたんだよ。
well, I was thinking about the show, and cleared it for them.
当たり前じゃん。
Obviously.
あ、なるほどね。分かってたか。いや、まさかチョコの方が学力テスト...
Ah, I see. You knew it. Wait, didn't Choco score higher in the academic test...
上位だったとか、チョコ口が裂けても言えなーい。
My lips are sealed about being higher ranked than you.
そうだよマジでもう、えー。
Exactly, seriously... geez.
え、次行く、次。次。
Well, next one, next. Next.
チョコちゃん、ちょっとこのままいてよ。うん。
Choco-chan, stay here with me for a bit. Okay?
あ、チョコいた方がいい？
Oh, do you want me to stay?
チョコいてよ。
Please stay.
しょうがないな。もう、あくあ様がいてほしいっていうなら、チョコいちゃおっかな。
I guess I have no choice. Since Aqua-sama wants me here, I'll stay.
じゃ、大丈夫。じゃ、大丈夫。
Then it's fine. It's fine.
え、何？そんなこと言わないであくあ様。せっかく、せっかく来たのに！
Eh, what? Don't say that, Aqua-sama. I came all this way!
え、じゃあ次は、次は次は。
Okay, then next is, next, next.
チョコちゃん、次の問題、お願いします！
Choco-chan, next problem, please!
ん？やっぱあくあ様がいてほしいって可愛くおねだりしたから、現れたの。
Hmm? I appeared because you cute-ly begged me to stay.
一緒に迷子になったの。あたしとチョコちゃん。
We're lost together. You and me, Choco-chan.
いや、チョコね、ずっとここに閉じ込められてるんだよね。
Actually, Choco has been trapped here for ages.
そう、なんかね、出れなくて。
Yeah, I just couldn't get out.
あ、そうなの？あ、じゃ、一緒に出ようね。一緒に出ようね。
Oh, really? Then let's get out together. Let's get out together.
一緒に連れてってくださいね、あくあ様。
Please take me with you, Aqua-sama.
何これ？「2羽と1匹が秘密を知っている」
What's this? "Two birds and one animal know the secret."
「7、8、4」。これレバーがある。
"7, 8, 4". There's a lever here.
レバーがある。え、これ、どういうこと？レバーを引くってこと？
There's a lever. What does this mean? Should I pull the lever?
そう、これレバーを押すと、この絵が変わります。
Yes, if you push this lever, the picture changes.
あ、でも、今んとこ2羽と1人だよね。
Oh, but right now there are two birds and one person.
ちょっとレバー引いてみてもいい？本当に引いてみてもいいの？
Can I try pulling the lever? Can I really pull it?
じゃあちょっと、ぺこらちゃんの絵の書いてある下のレバーを引きます！
Then, I'm pulling the lever under Pekora-chan's picture!
ドドンと！お願いします！
Bam! Here we go!
お！さかまた。え、これさ、全部やってみた方がいいよね。
Oh! Sakamata. Well, I should try them all, right?
まあまあまあ、一応ね、見といたほうがいいと思う。
Well, well, well, I think you should take a look, just in case.
おかゆちゃんのとこも引きます。はい、ドドン！
I'll pull Okayu-chan's too. Okay, dodon!
ドドン！
Dodon!
スバル！
Subaru!
おおー、ほほほ。
Oh, ho ho ho.
1は、1は、1は、1は。
1 is, 1 is, 1 is, 1 is.
ちょっと、じゃあ、ぼたんちゃんのとこも行きます。ドドン！
Wait, then I'll go to Botan-chan's too. Dodon!
ドドン！
Dodon!
ええー？ おかゆ？
Huh? Okayu?
おっと、これは...
Whoops, this is...
真ん中が私だったら、ねえ、まあ、三角関係の出来上がりなわけ。
If I were in the middle, well, we'd have a love triangle.
私のことを奪い合う三角関係。
A love triangle fighting over me.
違うのを引き合いに出すなお前は。
Don't bring up something else, you!
あ、違う？
Oh, not that?
それはね、ちょっと取り合いになっちゃうね。
That would be a bit of a struggle.
え、でも、もう1羽足りない。
Wait, but we're missing one more 'wa'.
もう1羽足りない。
Missing one more 'wa'.
しかも動物が3匹いる。どうしよう。
And there are three animals. What should I do?
え、どういうこと？ 2羽と1匹。2羽、まあ、1匹。
Wait, what does it mean? 2 'wa' and 1 'hiki'.
1回じゃあ元に戻してみます？
Shall we try resetting it once?
そうだね。全部戻そう。
That's right. Let's reset everything.
1回じゃあ一番最初の元に戻しましょうか。
Shall we go back to the very beginning once?
シオン、スバル、おかゆ... え？
Shion, Subaru, Okayu... huh?
5、3、7。2羽は、2羽は、2羽。
5, 3, 7. 2 'wa' is, 2 'wa' is, 2 'wa'.
ええー？
Huh?
そうだよ。2羽。
That's right. 2 'wa'.
2羽。
2 'wa'.
7。
7.
377。
377.
7。
7.
ちなみに、ここにある数字が脱出の鍵となりそうですね。
By the way, it looks like these numbers will be the key to escaping.
ねね、8。ねね、8。
Nene, 8. Nene, 8.
2羽と1匹ね。ぼたんちゃんが秘密を知っている。
2 'wa' and 1 'hiki'. Botan-chan knows the secret.
2羽！
2 'wa'!
2羽。
2 'wa'.
1匹。
1 'hiki'.
1、き、き、き？
1, hi, hi, hiki?
2羽と1匹ね。
2 'wa' and 1 'hiki'.
えー、わかんない！
I don't get it!
えー、わかんないの？
You don't get it?!
え、ヒント、ヒント、ヒント、ヒント。
Wait, hint, hint, hint, hint.
え、じゃあ... これは、数え方にヒントがあるかもしれないですね。
Well, then... this might have a hint in how things are counted.
なるほど。
I see.
あ、1頭だからぼたんちゃんは違うんだ。ぼたんちゃん違う。
Oh, it's 1 'tou', so Botan-chan is different. Botan-chan is different.
本当に？
Really?
で、ここおかゆだったよね。おかゆが1匹だから。
And this was Okayu, right? Because Okayu is 1 'hiki'.
おかゆ。
Okayu.
おかゆ、スバル、ぺこらちゃん。
Okayu, Subaru, Pekora-chan.
本当に？
Really?
2羽と、ぺこらちゃんがうさぎだから。
2 'wa' and... because Pekora-chan is a rabbit.
うさぎ。
Rabbit.
うさぎって1羽じゃない？
Isn't a rabbit 1 'wa'?
うさぎって...
A rabbit is...
1羽って言うのかな。
I wonder if you say 1 'wa'.
1羽って言うのかしらね。
I wonder if they say 1 'wa'.
え、本当にそれでいいの？
Wait, are you really okay with that?
じゃあ、ちょっと真ん中をスバルにして。
Then, let's put Subaru in the middle.
じゃあ、真ん中レバーを引きます。
Pulling the middle lever.
お願いします。
Please.
で、ぼたんちゃんをおかゆに。
And Botan-chan to Okayu.
え？ 羽って言うのかな。
Wait, is it 'wa'?
ぼたんちゃんのレバーも引く。
Pulling Botan-chan's lever too.
でもこれ... これだったら当てはまる。
But this... if it's this, it fits.
だってこの裏シオンちゃんだから。どっちの動物でも、シオンちゃん動物じゃないから。
Because Shion-chan is behind this. Whichever animal it is, she isn't an animal.
いや、でも。
No, but...
でも、シオン様は魔女っ子だから何でもなれちゃう気がするな。
But Shion-sama is a witch girl, so I feel like she can turn into anything.
そんなこと言われたら困っちゃうよ。そんなこと。え、どう、これ？
If you say that, I'm in trouble. That. Wait, what do you think of this?
え、どう？
Wait, how is it?
いや、スバル公式として羽と言うのか、羽と読むのか。
Well, as official Subaru, do they say 'wa' or read it as 'wa'?
匹と読むのかに寄る気がするけど。
I feel like it depends on if they read it as 'hiki'.
まあでもスバルはアヒルだから。
Well, but Subaru is a duck after all.
スバルはアヒルだから。
Subaru is a duck after all.
はい！ ファイナルアンサー！
Yes! Final answer!
本当にいいの？ 変えられないかもしれませんよ。
Is it really okay? You might not be able to change it.
やだ。
No way.
この後みんなのところに帰れなくなっちゃうかも。
After this, you might not be able to go back to everyone.
やばい、めっちゃ圧かけられてんだけど。
Oh no, I'm getting so much pressure.
ねえ、やめて、やめて。え、ねえ、みんな誰か助けて。
Hey, stop it, stop it. Wait, hey, everyone, someone help me.
やばい、やばい、圧が。
Oh no, oh no, the pressure.
待って。でも。
Wait. But.
2羽、1匹、2羽と1匹ね。
2 'wa', 1 'hiki', 2 'wa' and 1 'hiki'.
え、多分うさぎを羽と呼ぶんだよ、現代日本では。
Wait, I think rabbits are called 'wa' in modern Japan.
なるほどね。
I see.
そうそうそう。どうだ！
Right, right, right. How's that?!
ファイナルアンサー！
Final answer!
正解です！！
It's correct!!
やったー！
Yay!
え、うさぎって羽って読むんだ。
Oh, so rabbits are read as 'wa'.
あ、スバル、アヒルだ。
Ah, Subaru is a duck.
そう。うさぎは羽。
Right. Rabbits are 'wa'.
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
そうだ！ 絶対あくあ様わかんないと思ったわ、この問題。
I knew it! I totally thought Aqua-sama wouldn't know this problem!
いや、消去法だったかも。
Well, maybe it was a process of elimination.
シオンちゃんがその人間だから違うかなっていう消去法だった、正直。
Honestly, it was a process of elimination because Shion-chan is a human.
なるほど！
I see!
もしシオン様がころね様とかだったら迷ってた。
If Shion-sama were Korone-sama or someone else, I would have been confused.
おかゆが逆かなって思えてた。
I might have thought Okayu was the other way around.
やった！ 消去法だよ、完全に。
Yay! It's a complete process of elimination!
次はちょっと...
Next is a bit...
今度からは写真入れ替え...
From now on, I'll swap the photos...
やったー！
Yay!
やったやったやったー！
Yay yay yay!
おっ？
Oh?
ほら！
Look!
じゃあ、先ほど数字に書かれてたのは何番でしたか？
Then, what were the numbers written earlier?
え？ 7... 7
Eh? 7... 7
あれ、覚えてない、もしかして？ あれ？
Oh, don't you remember? Maybe? Oh?
あ、やべ、何番だっけ？
Ah, crap, what numbers were they?
ああー！ 7番、1番、7番...
Aaah! No. 7, No. 1, No. 7...
これ分からないと脱出できないですよ？
You can't escape if you don't know this, you know?
やばい、何だっけ？ 7、3...
Crap, what was it? 7, 3...
7、3、7、3...
7, 3, 7, 3...
7、3？
7, 3?
いや、愛注入5,000円があればね、覚えてるかもしれません
Well, if there was a 5,000 yen Love Injection, I might remember.
やばいやばい、何だっけ何だっけ...
Crap crap, what was it, what was it...
えー？ わかんない？
Eh? You don't know?
じゃあネネちゃんがやってたの覚えて... え、知りたい、ちょこちゃん知りたいです！
Then do you remember what Nene-chan did... Eh, I want to know, Choco-chan, I want to know!
え、じゃあ可愛くちょこにおねだりしてくれないと教えてあげられないかも
Eh, then unless you beg Choco cutely, I might not tell you.
445... 445... 開け！ 開け！
445... 445... Open! Open!
あくたんの可愛いおねだり聞きたいな、ちょこ
I want to hear Akutan's cute begging, Choco.
あ、1、あ、8、9、10、20... あー、わかんなくなっちゃった
Ah, 1, ah, 8, 9, 10, 20... Ah, I'm all confused now.
あーあくたわかんないね、あくたわかんないね
Ah, Akuta doesn't know, Akuta doesn't know.
お願いします...
Please...
お願いします... お願いします...
Please... Please...
みんなのことも大好きだから教えてほしいにゃって言ってくれない？
Why don't you say 'I love everyone after all, so please tell me, nya'?
うるせー！ 445しか書いてくんねーんだもん、もういいよだ！ やだ！
Shut up! They only write 445, I've had enough! No! I don't want to!
ちょこちゃんお願いします
Choco-chan, please.
うるせー！ 445でもやめろ！
Shut up! Stop with the 445 too!
お願いしましゅ... お願いしましゅ...
Please... Please...
445ちょっと開かないんだわ
445 just won't open.
お願いしましゅ... お願いしましゅ... お願いしましゅ...
Please... Please... Please...
あくあ教えてほしいな、ちゅるんってしてほしいな
I want Aqua to tell me, I want you to do 'churun'.
みんなのこと大好きだからあくあ教えてほしいな
I love everyone, so I want Aqua to tell me.
あくあ教えてほしいな、お願いします
I want Aqua to tell me, please.
教えて...
Tell me...
しょうがないわね、もう
I guess I have no choice, geez.
何？
What?
じゃあ、正解は...
Well then, the correct answer is...
731です
It's 731.
731... 731... 731... 731...
あ、入った！ あ、入った！
Ah, it went in! Ah, it went in!
ちょこのおかげさま、一緒に連れてってくれるんですよね？
Thanks to Choco, you'll take me with you, right?
よし、飲むぞ！
Alright, I'm drinking it!
あれ、聞いてる、あくあ様？ あくあ様？
Huh, are you listening, Aqua-sama? Aqua-sama?
出口の帰り道、あ、思い出した！
The way back to the exit, ah, I remembered!
あ、あくあ様、聞いてます？ ちょこの話
Ah, Aqua-sama, are you listening? To Choco's story.
あれ、美味しい、これ
Oh, this is delicious.
あれ、あくあ様？
Huh, Aqua-sama?
あー、やばい、脱出できる！ みんな待っててね！
Ah, crap, I can escape! Everyone, wait for me!
あくあ？ あくあ？
Aqua? Aqua?
ちょ、置いてかないで！ あくあ様！ ちょこも出してー！
Wait, don't leave me behind! Aqua-sama! Let Choco out too!
1, 2, 3, 4!
ディスコミュ星人
Disco Community Alien
作詞・作曲・編曲：ナユタン星人
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Nayutanya-seijin
待って 朝起きたらチェック通知
Wait, when I wake up in the morning, check notifications
カンガルー未来コミュニケーション
Kangaroo future communication
小粋なジョークで脱・通信
Escape communication with a smart joke
震わす親指で
With a trembling thumb
そんな時間だ 外に出なきゃ
It's that time, I have to go out
通るは勿論 裏通り
Taking the backstreets, of course
誰にも会わずに強引なはずが
Meant to be pushy without meeting anyone
まさかの気になるあの人が
Unexpectedly, that person I'm interested in...
おはよう！
Good morning!
え、あ、あの、なんでここにいるのですか？
Eh, ah, um, why are you here?
今日はその...
Today, well...
いや、え、あの、ち... いや、あの、え、え... うわあああ！
No, eh, um, ch... No, um, eh, eh... Uwaaaa!
ね、ね、ね コミュニケーション
Hey, hey, hey, communication
あなたと電波交信
Sending radio waves to you
まるでできない 言葉が出てない
I can't do it at all, no words are coming out
中々今じゃ無い
It's not quite right now
フィーリングで通じ合いたい
I want to connect through feelings
マジでできない 歌えはしない アー
I really can't do it, I can't sing, ahhh
星の数ほどの言葉の中から
From among as many words as there are stars
いそいそと何かを探してる
Restlessly searching for something
伝えたいのに しかし私は
I want to tell you, but I am...
ディスコミュ星人だったのだ
A disco-communication alien
フォー！
Whoo!
My world の名前はカストで思い通り
The name of my world is "Custom," just as I planned.
先手必勝 いざ ぶっ飛ぶ 諸見里
Winning by taking the lead, let's fly away like Morozato.
絶対 負けない 逃げない 初心ない 弱音は吐かない
Never losing, never running, no novice, never complaining.
スポットライトで キラキラ輝く キラットライクの私
Shining under the spotlight, the "Kirat-like" me.
あー 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
Ah, 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
アドレナリン 空回り だって それでも 笑顔で 昼昼に
Adrenaline's running in circles, but I'll still stay upbeat with a smile.
プリンセスでいいんです
Being a princess is just fine.
それしか似合わないんです
It's the only thing that suits me.
目を離さないで みんな 虜にするのが 私
Don't look away, it's my job to captivate everyone.
「かわいい！」
「Cute!」
えっ 急にみんなどうしたの？ ありがとう
Eh? What's gotten into everyone all of a sudden? Thanks!
いや そんなこと言われても 照れるというか 何というか
I mean, hearing that makes me blush, or something...
「かわいい！」
「Cute!」
いや 困ったな ありがとう 嬉しいな
Gee, I'm at a loss. Thank you, I'm happy.
私も… あ 夢か
I also... Oh, it was a dream.
ディ・ディ・ディ・ディスココミュニケーション
Di-Di-Di-Disco communication
あなたの感情予想
Predicting your emotions
まるで できない 答えが出ない
I just can't do it, I can't find the answer.
ちゅ・ちゅ・ちゅが足りないくらい
As if there aren't enough "Chu-Chu-Chu"s.
フィーリングで感じ合って
Let's feel each other through vibes.
そのまま溶けて どっか そんな マッサージュ
Melting away just like that, somewhere... like a massage.
ディ・ディ・ディ・ディスココミュニケーション
Di-Di-Di-Disco communication
解像度 レディネーション
Resolution Readiness
ガチでできない 伝わりゃしない
Seriously, I can't do it, I can't get it across.
夢の中ならうまくできるの
I can do it well in my dreams.
だけどリアルじゃできやしない
But I can't do it in reality.
最低ほど 踊る心は 同じ言語じゃないみたいなら
The more things go south, the more my heart dances, as if we don't speak the same language.
文字数と言葉は捨てるよ
I'll throw away character counts and words.
気持ちはほらここにあるよ
See, my feelings are right here.
伝えてみるよ だって私は ディスコミュ星人
I'll try to convey them, because I'm a "Discom-Alien."
だ・だ・だ・だ・だ・だ・だ・だ・だ・だ・だ・だ
Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da-Da
あ なんでもないです
Ah, it's nothing.
あ
Ah
湊あくあ セカンドワンマンライブ 開催決定！
Minato Aqua Second One-man Live confirmed!
皆さまどうもこんあくあ、湊あくあです。
Hello everyone, Kon-Aqua! I'm Minato Aqua.
この度、湊あくあのソロライブが開催決定！
I've decided to hold my next solo live!
あくあ色スーパー☆ドリームから1年半、みんなとの約束、守りに来たよ。
It's been a year and a half since "Aqua-iro Super Dream," and I've come to keep my promise.
2022年1月28日 金曜日 豊洲PITにて開催！
It will be held on Friday, January 28, 2022, at Toyosu PIT!
現地来場チケットの1次先行&SPWNでの配信チケット発売開始！
First round of pre-sales for venue tickets and streaming tickets on SPWN are now on sale!
湊あくあ初の有観客ライブ！
Minato Aqua's first live with an audience!
へんてこな衣装のNEKOに導かれて 銀河一のアイドルメイドが「わんだ～☆らんど」に迷い込む!?
Guided by a NEKO in strange attire, the galaxy's #1 idol maid wanders into "Wonderland"!?
あくあ色 in わんだ～☆らんど
Aqua-iro in Wonderland
あ、今名前ダサいって思った？
Ah, did you just think the name was tacky?
ちょっと、ねぇ、可愛いでしょ、ねぇ、ってば！
Hey, come on, it's cute, right? Hey!
ララララ…
La la la la...
ということで、皆さん！重大発表、見てくれましたか？
So, everyone! Did you see the major announcement?
ということで、なんと！湊あくあ、ソロライブが決定しました！
So, finally! A Minato Aqua solo live has been confirmed!
イェーイ！
Yay!
湊あくあワンマンライブ2022、
Minato Aqua One-man Live 2022,
あくあ色 in わんだ～☆らんどということで、ありがとうございます！
"Aqua-iro in Wonderland." Thank you!
えー、2020年の8月にね、ファーストワンマンをやらせていただいて、
Uh, in August 2020, I had my first one-man live,
来年もできたらいいねなんて話をして、絶対やるよなんて話をしていたんですけどもね、
and we talked about how it would be nice to do it again next year, and I said I definitely would,
いろんなね、まあこのご時世だったり、いろんな事情もあって、なかなかできるかなできないかなっていう状況だったんですが、
but due to the current situation and various circumstances, I wasn't sure if it would be possible,
えー、来年、1月の28日に、なんとワンマンライブやらせていただくことになりました！ありがとう、みんな！
but finally, it's been decided that I'll be doing a one-man live on January 28 next year! Thank you, everyone!
ということで、えー、今回、がお先生にキービジュアルを書いてもらいました！がおパパ、見てるー？
So, for this one, Gaou-sensei drew the key visual! Gaou-papa, are you watching?
今日、がおパパがね、Twitterでね、なんか、あの、ちょっと、今日おっぱいの日らしくて、それでなんか書いて、
Today, Gaou-papa tweeted... apparently today is "Boob Day," so he drew something,
あ、湊あくあちゃんも、えー、なんか重大発表ありましたみたいな感じでね、ツイートしてました。
and then he tweeted like, "Oh, and Minato Aqua-chan had a major announcement too."
おい、許せんな。私のちょっと、なんか、ちょっと脱がせた癖に、重大発表ありますよみたいなことをね、あの、ツイートしてました。許せねえ。
Hey, that's unforgivable! Even though he drew me showing some skin, he just tweeted "there's a major announcement" like an afterthought. Unforgivable!
あはは、いや、いつもありがとうございます。可愛いの書いてくださってます。今回もこんなに可愛いのを…
Hahaha, no, thank you as always. He always draws such cute things. And this time, it's so cute too...
あくあ色 in わんだー☆らんど♪
2022.1.28 Fri 豊洲PIT
Aqua-Iro in Wonderland
Jan 28, 2022 (Fri) at Toyosu PIT
描いてくださいました！
She drew it for me!
かわいい。え、めっちゃかわいくない？正直。
Cute. Eh, isn't it super cute? Honestly.
やばいよね。めっちゃかわいい。
It's amazing, right? Super cute.
そしてライブのロゴは、KOME WORKSの島田みのりさんに作っていただきました。
And the live logo was created by Minori Shimada of KOME WORKS.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
すごいかわいい、おしゃれなロゴをね、作っていただきまして。
They made such a cute and stylish logo for me.
そして、キービジュアルの、このネコ！
And the cat in this key visual!
ネコにもね、衣装が今回あります。なんかいつの間にかさ...
The cat also has a costume this time. Somehow, before I knew it...
...隣にいるんだけど。ネコ。おかしくない？
...it's right next to me. The cat. Isn't that weird?
それは私がこうやっててたらさ、今日、ここにいたらネコがいるんだけど。
When I was doing this, like, I was here today and the cat was there.
え？なんか当たり前みたいになってる。
Eh? It's like it's taken for granted.
ね！ということで、キービジュアルのネコの衣装原案はサメタ先生です。
Right! So, the costume concept for the cat in the key visual is by Sameta-sensei.
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
ということで、ちょっとね、あのー詳細などを詳しく見ていきたいんだけども。
So, I'd like to take a closer look at the details and such.
来年、2022年の1月28日金曜日より、
Next year, starting from Friday, January 28th, 2022,
豊洲PITで行われることになりまして、配信チケットももちろんあります。
it will be held at Toyosu PIT, and of course there are streaming tickets too.
でね、一昨年は実は、本当は現地でやる予定もあったかなかったか、あれなんですけども、
And, two years ago, actually, whether there were plans to do it on-site or not...
オンラインライブで、なんとね、そう、
...it ended up being an online live, and, well...
やりたかった... 本当はやりたかったんだけどオンラインライブになってしまいましたという感じだったんですが、
I wanted to... I really wanted to do it, but it became an online live, that's how it was.
今年は、来年か。来年はついに、私、実は初めてなんです。
This year—no, next year. Next year, finally, it's actually a first for me.
初めての、えー、現地ありでのソロライブをさせていただくことになりました！
I'll be having my first solo live with an on-site audience!
ありがとうございます！やーマジで嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm seriously so happy!
ずっとね、やっぱライブやりたーいって言ってたので、
I've always been saying, you know, "I want to do a live!"
できてね、本当に嬉しいです。そして場所は豊洲PIT。
So I'm really happy I can do it. And the venue is Toyosu PIT.
一番初めのホロライブの全体ライブが、確か豊洲PITだったかな？
The very first Hololive all-member live was at Toyosu PIT, I believe?
で、今回はね、やらせていただくことになりました。すごく思い出深い地ではありますけれども、
And this time, I'll be performing there. It's a place full of memories,
よろしくお願いします！
but I'm looking forward to it!
そして、えー、会場、か、会場...
And, the venue... doors open...
会場会場ってなんかすごい変な感じだね。
"Venue venue" sounds really strange, doesn't it?
会場の開場時間は17時。そして配信の開場は17時半。
The venue doors open at 17:00. And the stream venue opens at 17:30.
そして開演は18時です！わー！
And the performance starts at 18:00! Wow!
配信はSPWNで行われます。
The stream will be on SPWN.
公演放送後のアーカイブは、2022年の2月28日まで何度でも見放題ができます。
The archive after the show will be available for unlimited viewing until February 28, 2022.
とっても、お得です！お得なんです！
It's a very good deal! It really is!
チケット購入は2022年2月28日まで可能です。
Tickets can be purchased until February 28, 2022.
みんな買ってね。去年はね、ちょっとサイトが落ちてやばいみたいなことがあったんですけど、
Please buy them, everyone. Last year the site crashed and things got crazy,
今年は大丈夫。もう万全を期しているので、今年こそは...
but this year is fine. We're fully prepared, so this year...
チケットページ落としません。落とさせません。湊あくあ、いつもね、
I won't let the ticket page go down. I won't let it crash. Minato Aqua is always...
破壊神と言われているんですが、今回は絶対にサイトは落とさない。
...called a God of Destruction, but I definitely won't let the site crash this time.
今回気合を入れてますので、皆さんも気合を入れてチケット戦争に臨んでください。お願いします！
I'm putting my heart into this, so please put yours into the ticket war as well. Please!
そして、えー、デジタルフラスタというのもあって、
Also, there's a thing called Digital Flower Stand,
ま、今回ね、コロナウイルス感染予防の観点から当日フラワースタンドやプレゼント、
well, this time, from the perspective of COVID-19 prevention, flower stands, presents,
お手紙を受け取ることがなんとできないんです。ごめんなさい。
and letters cannot be accepted on the day. I'm sorry.
あー、ごめんね。
Ah, sorry.
その代わりに、デジタルフラスタというのを送ってもらうことができます。
Instead, you can send a "Digital Flower Stand."
こちらの申し込み締め切りなどは、特設ホームページ、
The application deadlines and such can be found on the special website,
デジタルフラスタ特設サイトのSPWNをチェックしてください。
check the SPWN Digital Flower Stand special site.
そして、ここからは湊あくあ重大発表ではなく、
And from here, it's not the Minato Aqua Major Announcement,
公演ハッシュタグというのがございまして、湊あくあソロライブです！
but the event hashtag: #MinatoAquaSoloLive!
なので、ライブの応援は湊あくあソロライブにたくさん呟いてくれると嬉しいです。
So, for live support, I'd be happy if you'd tweet a lot with #MinatoAquaSoloLive.
今からでもたくさん呟いちゃってください。1行だけでもいいんで、
Please start tweeting a lot even now. Even just one line is fine,
よかったらいっぱい呟いてください。お願いします！
please tweet a lot if you'd like. Please!
みんなの反応、あとで見るからね。
I'll be checking everyone's reactions later.
さらに、ライブのグッズをちょっと紹介します。
Furthermore, let me introduce the live goods.
ライブにマストで必要な、Tシャツ、ライト、タオルがセットになった、
We have a set of the essentials for a live: T-shirt, light, and towel,
わんだーせっとね。あくあ色インワンダーランドってさ、かわいいでしょ？
the "Wanda-Setto." "Aqua-Iro in Wonderland"—it's cute, right?
ダサいとか言わない。あくあ色インワンダーランド。わんだー...
Don't say it's uncool. "Aqua-Iro in Wonderland." "Wanda-a-a"...
ランドーだ。おふだから。みんな頼むよ。
...Land. It's a pun. So everyone, please.
はい、ということでね、わんだーせっとの特典として、
Yes, so, as a bonus for the "Wanda-Setto,"
今回のライブのパンフレットと、私からの手紙がついて... おい何だこれ？
it comes with the live pamphlet and a letter from me... Hey, what's this?
わんだーせっと
(Tシャツ, アクリルプレートライト, タオル)
Wonder Set
(T-shirt, Acrylic Plate Light, Towel)
台本にさ、私じゃなくて「あっちし」って書いてあったんだけど。
In the script, it says "attishi" instead of "atashi" (me).
どういうこと？ねえ。台本に「あっちし」ってなってんだけど。おかしいだろこれ。
What does this mean? Look. It says "attishi" in the script. This is weird.
おい誰が書いたんだこの台本。えー、わんだーせっとは在庫が...
Hey, who wrote this script? Anyway, the Wonder Set is in stock...
なくなり次第終了となりますので
It will end as soon as it's gone
ぜひ気をつけて買ってね。早いもの勝ちだよ。
So please be careful and buy it. It's first-come, first-served.
手紙はね、わんだーせっとにしか付きません。
The letter only comes with the Wonder Set.
何て書いてあるかは、これを買った人のお楽しみです！
What's written in it is a surprise for those who buy it!
次は、後日発送のグッズです。こちら！
Next is the goods for later shipment. Here they are!
アクリルスタンドやアクキー、タペストリー、缶バッジセット、
Acrylic stands, acrylic keychains, tapestries, can badge sets,
カトラリーセットなどもご用意しました！
and cutlery sets are also available!
アクリルスタンドとキーホルダーですけれども、
Here are the acrylic stands and keychains,
かわいい！かわいいなこれ！えー！
So cute! These are so cute! Wow!
そしてね、もう一つね、カトラリーセットなどもグッズ2かな？
And then, another thing, the cutlery set and more in Goods 2?
グッズ2のほうに、こちら！
In Goods 2, here!
タペストリー、缶バッジセット、カトラリーセットと。
Tapestry, can badge set, and cutlery set.
やば！
Wow!
これね、このカトラリーセット、スプーンとかにねこ付いてんだよ！やばくない？ねこ！
Look at this cutlery set, there are cats on the spoons! Isn't that crazy? Cats!
ははっ！ねこ付いてんの！めちゃくちゃかわいいでしょこれ！
Haha! There are cats on them! Isn't this super cute?!
ということで、どのグッズもめちゃくちゃかわいいので、
So, all the items are super cute,
グッズの注文詳細、注意事項は各ショップのページや、
so please check the details and precautions for ordering goods on each shop page,
特設サイトホームページのグッズページの注意書きをチェックしてください！
or the notes on the goods page of the special website!
全部ね、概要欄とかにね、なんと更新されておりますから！
Everything has been updated in the description box and so on!
はい。よかったらぜひ皆さん、購入してみてはいかがでしょうか！
Yes. Please consider buying them if you'd like!
そして、チケットもね、なんと、もう今から発売なのかな？
And the tickets, too... are they on sale from now?
そうです、発売です！
Yes, they are on sale!
グッズも今から買えちゃうのかな？
I wonder if we can buy the goods from now too?
ということで、みんな概要欄から、急げ、チェック、チェック、チェック、チェック、チェック、チェック！
So, everyone, hurry up and check, check, check, check, check, check from the description box!
はい！ということでね、みんな、よかったら、お手元にぜひね。
Yes! So everyone, please get them in your hands.
『あくあ色 in わんだーらんど』、楽しみにしててね！
Look forward to "Aqua Iro in Wonderland"!
あ、そう、10時からです。10時からだって、みんな！
Oh, right, it's from 10:00. It starts at 10:00, everyone!
10時から！10時から開始らしいわ、みんな！10時からです。10時から。オッケー？
From 10:00! It seems it starts at 10:00, everyone! From 10:00. 10:00. Okay?
みんな、まだだわ。まだでした。
Everyone, not yet. Not yet.
グッズ、22時でした。すいませんでした！
The goods start at 22:00. I'm sorry!
はははっ！22時からね、これ終わったらみんな、まだあるから！まだあるから！
Hahaha! From 22:00, okay? After this ends, there's more! There's more!
告知タイムだと思ったでしょ。ちゃうから！
You thought the announcement time was over, right? It's not!
ちゃんと私最後までやりきるから、この重大発表ライブ。ちゃんと最後まで見ててください。
I'll see this major announcement live through to the end. Please watch until the end.
そしてね、さっき見てもらった映像で、みんなが知らない曲が多分流れてたよね。
And, in the video you just saw, a song you probably don't know was playing, right?
「きらきら〜♪」って、みんな聞いてた？
Did everyone hear "Kira kira~♪"?
「あれ、この曲知らねえな」って思った人、たくさんいると思うんですけども、
I think many people were like, "Wait, I don't know this song."
今日、この重大発表を楽しみにしてくれてたみんなのために、
For everyone who was looking forward to today's major announcement,
新曲を、歌っちゃいまーす！
I'm going to sing a new song!
ということで、なんとですね、この曲は、あのね、私ね、
And, this song is, you know, for me...
「ヴァンパイア」とか「シンデレラ」とかね、歌ってみた上げさせていただいてますけど、
I've uploaded covers of "Vampire" and "Cinderella",
DECO*27さんが作ってくださった楽曲です！わー！
and this is a song created by DECO*27! Yay!
すごーい！豪華すぎる！いいんですか！？
Amazing! It's too luxurious! Is this okay?!
そして、今日の24時からダウンロード＆ストリーミングが配信開始となりますので、
And download and streaming will start from midnight tonight,
そちらもよろしくお願いします！チェックしてね！
so please check that out too! Check it!
一足先にライブでは聴けますが、もう一回聴きたーいって人はよかったら、
You can hear it first in the live performance, but for those who want to hear it again,
いろんなストリーミングサイトいっぱいありますので、そちらでダウンロード、ストリーミング聴いてみてください！
there are many streaming sites, so please download or stream it there!
そして、来年1月28日のワンマンに向けて、この後も続々と、
And leading up to the one-man live on January 28 next year, after this,
これだけじゃなく、他にも新曲を制作していて、次々と発表されていくので、楽しみに待っててね！
not just this one, but other new songs are being produced and will be announced one after another, so look forward to them!
マジでね、いい曲ばっかだから！マジでやばいです。マジでやばいです。
Seriously, they're all good songs! It's seriously amazing. It's seriously amazing.
正直言います。マジでやばいです！
I'll be honest. It's seriously amazing!
ということで、今日はね、みんな遊びに来てくれて、本当にありがとう！
So, thank you all so much for coming to hang out today!
じゃあ、早速、新曲を歌おうかなと思うんですけど、いいですか？
Now, I'm thinking of singing the new song right away, is that okay?
ははっ！みんなまだね、名前も知らないからね、あの曲の. ね？
Haha! Everyone doesn't even know the name of that song yet. Right?
じゃあね、今回はね、振りもありで歌っていこうと思っておりますので、よろしくお願いします！
So, this time, I'm going to sing it with choreography, so please look forward to it!
ということで、今日は見に来てくれて本当にありがとう！ライブよかったら楽しみにしててね！
So, thank you so much for watching today! Please look forward to the live performance!
それでは、聴いてください。 『きらきら』。
Now, please listen. "Kirara".
きらきら
Kirara
作詞・作曲：DECO*27
Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
今日のオハヨウ　少しドキドキするの
Today's "Good Morning", I'm a little nervous
選ばれるかって不安になって　ああ
Worried if I'll be chosen, ah
ダメなところ　ばかりで嫌になるな
Hating myself for all my flaws
進んでみたって上手くいかない　けど
Even if I move forward, it doesn't go well, but
ほら もっともっと出したいわ お腹いっぱい代わりたくて振り絞ったんだ
Look, I want to bring out more and more, I squeezed it all out wanting to change completely
描いた未来を好きになりたいから
Because I want to learn to love the future I envisioned
きらきらと輝こうか 間違えちゃっても大丈夫
Shall we shine brightly? It's okay even if we make mistakes
できないことできるように なれるよ 先は長いから
We'll be able to do what we can't do now, because there's a long way ahead
疲れちゃったら止まろうか 少し眠ったら元通り
Shall we stop if we get tired? Once we sleep a bit, we'll be back to normal
したいことしたいように それじゃ私じゃないでしょ
Doing what I want, the way I want, otherwise it wouldn't be me
忘れないよこの思いは 重ねてもっと届くように
I won't forget these feelings, so that they stack up and reach further
変えられるんだ変えていくんだ きらきらしたいから
I can change, I'm going to change, because I want to sparkle
今日もおはよう 振り返る今日の私は
Good morning today too, looking back at myself today
ほんのちょっとだけ強くなれそう みたい
It feels like I might have become just a little bit stronger
来ない明日も 何だか自然な感じだ
Even a tomorrow that won't come feels somewhat natural now
いつも通りはもっと楽しくしてみたい
I want to try making the "usual" more fun
怖いよ実際だけどもう一回 乾いたハート振り絞っていこう
It's actually scary, but one more time, let's squeeze out our parched hearts
降りたい私が おいでおいでするから
Because the me that wants to step down is calling out "come here, come here"
未体験だよ
It's an unexperienced world
きらきらと輝こうか 間違えちゃっても大丈夫
Shall we shine brightly? It's okay even if we make mistakes
できないことできるように なれるよ 先は長いから
We'll be able to do what we can't do now, because there's a long way ahead
疲れちゃったら止まろうか 少し眠ったら元通り
Shall we stop if we get tired? Once we sleep a bit, we'll be back to normal
したいことしたいように それじゃ私じゃないでしょ
Doing what I want, the way I want, otherwise it wouldn't be me
忘れないよこの思いは
I won't forget these feelings
重ねてもっと届くように
So that they stack up and reach further
変えられるんだ変えていくんだ きらきらしたいから
I can change, I'm going to change, because I want to sparkle
重なる強さ
The strength of stacking up
ダメな私 ずっとずっと歌うよ
Even if I'm useless, I'll keep singing forever and ever
輝けること 変われちゃうこと
The fact that I can shine, the fact that I can change
ダメな私 ずっとずっと見ていてほしい
I want you to keep watching me forever, even if I'm useless
湊あくあ きらきら 作詞・作曲: DECO*27
Minato Aqua - Kira Kira / Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
みなさんどうも、こんあくあー！湊あくあです！
Hello everyone, Kon-Aqua! I'm Minato Aqua!
この度、湊あくあのソロライブが開催決定！
It's been decided that Minato Aqua's solo live will be held!
『あくあ色スーパー☆どり～む』から1年半、みんなとの約束、守りに来たよ！
A year and a half since "Aqua-iro Super☆Dream", I've come to keep my promise to everyone!
2022年1月28日、豊洲PIT＆オンラインで開催予定！
Scheduled to be held on January 28, 2022, at Toyosu PIT & online!
今年もみんなと会えるの楽しみだな！
I'm looking forward to seeing everyone again this year!
湊あくあ ワンマンライブ2022 『あくあ色 in わんだ～らんど♪』
Minato Aqua One-Man Live 2022 "Aqua-iro in Wonderland♪"
ねぇ、今名前ダサいって思った？
Hey, did you just think the name is lame?
ちょっと、こらー！でしょ！
Hey, cut it out!
ねぇってばー！
I mean it!